The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
Even within that brilliant history,
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
Despite being relatively unknown
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
and lacking a game record,
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
にもかかわらず—
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
A phantom sixth man.
幻のシックスマンがいた と
Let's fly now.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Let's try now.
Let's
fly
now.
Get
my
stage!
Let's
try
now.
Next
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Translation Check   AMS
Get
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Now!
Running into the middle of that exciting stage...
mu
ne
o
do
ru
su
tee
ji
e
ka
ke
a
ga
ru
do
ma
nna
ka
de
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Continually breakthrough your limits.
ka
gi
ri
na
ku
ri
n
ka
i
te
n
to
ppa
mi
se
te
yo
Timing       ninjacloud
We have dreams, we're fond of legends, everybody in the ring.
yu
me
ta
shi
na
mu
re
je
n
do
every
body
wa
no
na
ka
de
Don't hesitate, into the future, JUMP!
ma
yo
i
na
ku
mi
ra
i
e
no
JUMP
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
They all say they haven't fallen after they have.
o
chi
bu
re
te
na
i
to
o
chi
bu
re
te
ka
ra
i
u
ya
tsu
ba
kka
It's scary aiming at coming back from the dead but
ki
shi
ka
i
se
ne
ra
u
mi
chi
no
ri
ko
wa
ku
na
wa
i
ga
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
if the road is still blocked
ko
e
te
ku
ka
be
na
no
ni
tsu
u
ka
te
n
na
no
ni
Karaokes      KmE
after I've crossed all the barriers,
fu
sa
i
de
ru
na
ra
I need to realize I'm not alone.
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
ji
ka
ku
o
Slam it!
t
o
d
k
e
We have to set the rim on fire!
w
e
h
a
v
e
t
o
m
a
k
e
a
R
I
M
F
I
R
E
Let's combine our power and our minds.
a
w
s
e
r
o
p
w
e
r
n
o
a
k
n
o
m
i
n
d
Encoding      Your Mom
We don't need any excuses.
i
w
a
k
e
i
r
a
n
z
o
Gotta dream, exceed your limits, and war.
G
o
t
a
d
r
e
a
m
g
e
n
k
a
i
t
o
w
a
r
I need to face up to my common sense,
ta
chi
ha
da
ka
ru
no
wa
ri
ka
i
shi
su
gi
ta
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
joushiki to
which I know all too well,
kodoku no maibotsu
and bury my loneliness.
RIM
FIRE!!
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
Touou
Seirin
They doubled their score?
（高尾(たかお)）ダブルスコアだあ？
Touou's crazy!
ヤバくないスか 桐皇(とうおう)
誠凛(せいりん)がこれなら—
If Seirin lost that badly, we'd lose even worse.
ウチはもっと
ぼろ負けするんじゃないスか
Shut up, idiot!
（木村(きむら)）なんでだ アホ！
（高尾）あっ いてっ！
He's right. It's not that simple.
（大坪(おおつぼ)）そう単純な話でもないさ
For Midorima, Kagami was nearly the worst opponent he could have faced.
緑間(みどりま)にとって
火神(かがみ)は最悪に近い相性だった
But if it came down to stopping Aomine...
とはいえ
青峰(あおみね)を止められるかと言えば…
The Generation of Miracles' ace is off the charts.
とてつもないな
“キセキの世代”のエースは
See you later, Kise.
（緑間）じゃあな 黄瀬(きせ)
That was quick!
（黄瀬）はやっ！
ちょっとはショックとかないんスか
この結果に
Aren't you shocked at all by these results?
（緑間）オレより—
You should be worried about Kuroko instead of me.
黒子(くろこ)の心配をしたほうがいいのだよ
What?
Kuroko's basketball was completely useless against Aomine.
（緑間）青峰に黒子のバスケは
まったく通用しなかった
It must have been pretty psychologically damaging.
精神的にも相当なダメージだろう
Not only that, but Seirin is still a young team.
しかも誠凛はまだ若いチームだ
It won't be easy for them to come back from that overnight.
この修正を一晩でするのは
容易ではないのだよ
We can only hope it won't affect their remaining two games.
残り２試合に
影響がなければいいがな
Episode 19
On to a New Challenge
We destroyed our opponent in our first game of the championship league!
（若松(わかまつ)）初戦まずは圧勝
We know. You don't have to yell.
（今吉(いまよし)）分かっとる
そんな騒ぐなや
What?
I thought they'd be stronger,
considering they beat Shutoku.
（控え選手）いやあ
秀徳(しゅうとく)倒したから—
どんなもんかと思えば
はははっ
Especially No. 11, Kuroko, right?
（控え選手）特にあの11番
黒子だっけ？
終盤全然クソだし
He was absolute garbage towards the end!
He was real uptight about it until the very end.
最後までムキになってて
サブッとか思ったし
とっとと諦めりゃいいのに
He should've given up sooner.
For someone who didn't play, you sure have a big mouth. Shut up.
（青峰）
試合も出てねえのに—
ピーピーうるせえよ
（控え選手）ぐあ…
（若松）青峰！
Aomine!
何やってんだ 放せっ！
What are you doing? Let him go!
（控え選手）げほっ
なんだ 急に…
What's his problem?
Aomine...
（さつき）青峰君…
Damn it.
（火神）くそっ！
Everyone, we still have two more games against Meisei and Senshinkan!
（リコ）みんな！ 鳴成(めいせい)と泉真館(せんしんかん)
試合はまだ２つあるんだからね！
We don't have the time to be sad!
落ち込んでるヒマなんてないわよ！
Hey.
（火神）なあ
これが… 限界なのかもな
This might be our limit.
I thought we could go further.
正直 もっとやれると思ってた
けど このザマだ
But look at us.
圧倒的な力の前では—
In the face of overwhelming power,
I don't think we can win just by working together.
力を合わせるだけじゃ
勝てねえんじゃねえのか？
Tetsu,
（青峰）テツ…
I don't think you were wrong, but...
オマエの言ってたことは
間違ってねぇと思う
けど やっぱ—
I just can't.
ダメだわ
I'll never find what I'm looking for.
オレの欲しいもんは
絶対 見つかんねー
オレに勝てるのは オレだけだ
The only one who can beat me is me.
In the remaining two games, Kagami didn't play...
（リコ）残る２試合
火神君は欠場
and Kuroko experienced a sudden slump.
そして黒子君の突然の不調
今まで何度もチームを救ったパスは
見る影もなかった
Not even a shadow of the passes that had saved our team so many times before could be seen.
Seirin
Meisei
Kaijo Private High School
Hey!
（黄瀬）どーもっス
Kise...
（笠松(かさまつ)）黄瀬
Would you like to play some one-on-one?
先輩 ワンオンワン
しねえっスか？
Would I?
しねえっスかって—
I thought you went to watch the final game of the championship league.
オマエ 決勝リーグの最終戦—
見に行ったんじゃねえのか？
（黄瀬）行きました
I did.
How'd it turn out?
結果はどうだったんだよ
It made me feel like playing basketball.
無性にバスケがしたくなったっス
聞いてねえよ
That's not what I'm asking!
えっ 結果気になんないっスか？
You're not curious about the results?
かみ合わねえな
I can't deal with you.
Let's go!
行きますよ
（笠松）あっ テメエ！
You bastard!
Even if they give everything they have, not every challenger can become a winner.
（リコ）全力を尽くしても—
挑む者すべてが
勝者となれるわけではない
Senshinkan
Seirin
We lost.
Senshinkan
Seirin
（リコ）私たちは負けた
Senshinkan
Seirin
Seirin High School's attempt at the Inter-High ended.
誠凛高校の
インターハイへの挑戦は—
終わった
だが すべてが
終わったわけではない
However, all was not lost.
Aida Riko
Sorry
We lost.
I see. I didn't make it in time.
（木吉(きよし)）そっか…
間に合わなかったか
When one thing ends, another begins.
（リコ）終わるということは
同時に始まりを意味する
In other words...
つまり…
Kiyoshi Teppei
But
It's not over yet
We were on to a new challenge.
（リコ）新しい挑戦へ
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Sasaki General Hospital
Because of your build, your legs take that much more damage.
（医者）
君は体格いいぶん—
足にかかる衝撃がものすごいわけ
Your body isn't strong enough to handle that yet.
（医者）ところが—
それを受け止めるだけの
体がまだできてない
You'll need flexibility and muscle training,
必要なのは柔軟と筋トレ
けどその前に—
but before that,
two weeks of complete rest.
２週間は絶対安静ね
（火神）オレは弱い
I'm weak.
青峰に手も足も出なかった
I couldn't do anything against Aomine.
どうすれば—
What do I need to do?
How can I... become stronger?
どうすればもっと強くなれる！？
（小金井(こがねい)）だあ…
（小金井）試合に負けたあとの
練習ほど 最悪なもんないよねー
Nothing is worse than practice after losing a game.
（伊月(いづき)）言うな
テンション下がる
Don't say that. You'll bring us all down.
Didn't we mess up a lot of our fast breaks during the Senshinkan game?
（小金井）てか泉真館戦
速攻のミス多くなかった？
A lot? Maybe two.
（伊月）多いっつーか
２つかな
Man, this sucks.
（小金井）あー ヤベーよー
スリーメンとか増えるよ 絶対
I bet we're going to do more three man drills.
1,5 ２倍
1.5 times, maybe twice as much!
（日向(ひゅうが)）いや…
No...
Why don't we try three times?
（リコ）３ いっとく？
T-Three times?
（小金井）さ… ３倍？
We just finished playing a game!
試合 終わったばっかなのに
We'll die!
（伊月）ほんと 死んじゃうって
What's that? Four?
え ４(し)？
All right, practice!
（小金井）しゃー 練習
Let's give it our best!
（伊月）気合い入れていくぞー
（部員たち）はい！
Yeah!
Gather 'round, everyone!
（日向）よーし ５５(ゴーゴー)やるぞ
集まれ！
Where's Kuroko? Is he skipping practice?
って 黒子は？ サボリか？
I'm not skipping.
（黒子）サボってません
え よし
てか 久しぶりだな この感じ
Oh, okay!
I haven't experienced that in a while.
And Number 2!
お そして２号(にごう)
（テツヤ２号）ワン
Today's the day...
（小金井）今日こそは！
（土田(つちだ)）止めるぞ 黒子！
We'll stop you, Kuroko!
ぬああ
Hey! Tsucchi, stop him!
（小金井）コラー！ ツッチー！
ちゃんと止めろ！
Koga, you're the one who said you'd stop him today!
（土田）コガだろ！
今日こそ止めるって言ったのは
No, it was you!
（小金井）いや オマエこそ！
Damn it!
I was worried about them,
but they're still their same old selves.
（リコ）心配してたけど
みんないつも通りね
黒子君も大丈夫そう
Kuroko seems all right too.
Of course, he isn't.
We tried so hard
あれだけ頑張って—
and still didn't make it to the Inter-High.
それでもインターハイには
行けなかった
みんな全然 入ってない
None of them are into it.
I guess it's too much to expect them to bounce back so soon.
すぐに立ち直れってのが無理か
Gather 'round!
（リコ）集合！
Everyone, do you remember what you said when you joined the team?
みんな 入部のときに言ったこと
覚えてる？
（１年生たち）あ…
Announce your goals here and now!
今年の目標を
宣言してもらいます！
さらに できなかったときは
ここから—
If you fail to achieve them,
you'll come back up here, strip naked,
and confess your feelings for the girl you love!
全裸で好きな子に
コクってもらいます
We're really...
（降旗(ふりはた)）あれ…
（福田(ふくだ)）やるの？
going to do that?
（河原(かわはら)）うえ…
次はもう負けられないわよ
分かってる？
You don't want to lose the next one.
Know why?
Winter's going to be cold.
冬は寒いわよ
（河原）え 冬？
Winter?
That's right!
そうよ！ 高校の頂点を
決める戦いは夏のインターハイ
The best high school is determined at the summer Inter-High.
そして冬の選抜
And also at the winter championship!
It is where the strongest teams fight it out for the year's biggest and final championship.
その年の最強を決める
最大最後のタイトル 通称—
Its name is...
The Winter Cup!
ウィンターカップ
That's where we'll put it all on the line!
すべてをぶつけるのはそこよ！
It's our last chance of the year.
今年 最後のチャンス か…
If we can't win this winter,
これで冬もダメだったら—
she'll really make us go naked.
全裸やるぞ
マジであの女は
うふ うふふっ
But isn't it the same level as the Inter-High?
（福田）けど
インハイと同等レベルでしょ
（降旗）やっぱ正直
きついよな
This is going to be tough.
（リコ）それなんだけど
日向君
About that, Hyuga.
もうすぐ帰ってくるわ
鉄平(てっぺい)が
It looks like he'll should be coming home soon... Teppei.
What?
え… マジ？
Seriously?
We might see a lot happen.
こりゃあ いろいろ起こる…
かもな
Uh, who's Teppei?
（降旗）先輩 あの—
鉄平さんって？
Oh yeah. The first years haven't met him yet.
ああ そうか
１年はまだ会ってないか
ウチの７番—
He's No. 7, our ace.
エースさ
それよか
大丈夫なのか 火神
What about Kagami? Is he going to be okay?
He's resting, but I told him to come watch us play.
（日向）安静らしいけど—
見学には来いって
言ってあんだけどな
もう１週間 見てねえな
I haven't seen him in a week.
He might be hurt, but he's got some balls to not show up.
（日向）いくらケガでも
バックレとはいい度胸だ
I'll hit him the next time I see him!
今度しばく！
黒子 クラス一緒だろ
何か知んねえ？
Kuroko, you're in his class, aren't you?
Do you know anything?
No. I haven't spoken to him.
いえ… しゃべっていないので
You could've asked him something!
聞けよ 少しは何か
Sorry.
すみません
Recently,
けど 最近—
it's been a little difficult for me to talk to Kagami.
火神君はちょっと
話しかけづらいので
お疲れさまです
Good work.
（テツヤ２号）クゥーン
（ドアの開閉音）
Is he okay?
（伊月）大丈夫か？
（日向）心配ないって
He'll be fine.
Not Kagami.
いや 火神じゃなくて—
I get the feeling something's wrong with Kuroko.
黒子さ
なんか変な気がする
It looks like he's run up against a wall or something.
ぶち当たってるんじゃないかな
壁みたいなものに
It's not just Kagami, but now it's Kuroko too.
（日向）ったく
火神だけじゃなくて黒子まで—
There's always more to worry about.
悩みはつきねえなあ
Uh, what's Teppei like?
（福田）あの 先輩
鉄平さんって
どんな人なんですか？
Huh? Oh...
If you haven't changed,
it means you haven't improved.
（青峰）同じってことは
成長してねえってことじゃねえか
Your basketball will never win.
オマエのバスケじゃ 勝てねえよ
（テツヤ２号）わん わん わん
（男子生徒）あっは
ほら来い
Come here!
あっはは よーしよし
Good boy, good boy!
（男子生徒）うう〜
（テツヤ２号）ワウワウ
（男子生徒）ハハッ なんかこいつ
君と似てない？
Don't you think he looks like you?
聞いていたとおり—
It's just like I heard.
You're not much good at anything besides passing.
パス以外は
からっきしなんだな
けど いいんじゃねえ
But who cares about that?
I like your basketball.
オレは好きだよ 君のバスケ
You're not wrong. You're just inexperienced.
間違っちゃいねえ
ただまだ未熟
That's all.
そんだけじゃん
That guy is weird.
（日向）ヤツは—
変人
What?
But I owe him.
でも恩人
オレをバスケに
誘ってくれたからな
He's the one who encouraged me to play basketball.
（男子生徒）アメちゃんいる？
Do you want some candy?
No, thank you.
（黒子）結構です
Really?
（男子生徒）ああ そう
And who may you be?
どちら様ですか？
Yeah, he's...
ああ あいつは…
（木吉）木吉鉄平
Kiyoshi Teppei.
...the man who created the Seirin High School basketball team.
（日向）誠凛高校バスケ部を
創った男だよ
Are you Kiyoshi?
木吉さん… ですか
Take the "ki" from "This tree, what is it? What is this tree?"
（木吉）
♪この木何の木 気になる木
Plus the "kichi" of "good luck," and it's Kiyoshi.
の 木に 大吉の吉で 木吉さ
ああ はい
I see.
Then take the "tetsu" in "dumbbell," and the "hira" in "lowly employee," and you get Teppei!
で 鉄アレイの鉄に
平社員の平で 鉄平だ
Um, do you want something?
（黒子）あの…
何かご用ですか？
（木吉）君は面白い
You're interesting.
（木吉）バスケってのは
ジェネラリスト—
Basketball is about generalists.
It's a sport for guys who can do everything.
つまり 何でもこなせるヤツの
スポーツだ
Put loosely, you'll be okay with five scorers who can pass.
乱暴な言い方をすれば—
パスを出せるスコアラーが
５人いればオッケー
That doesn't always work,
which is why you have positions,
まあ そうもいかねえから—
ポジションってもんが
あるわけだし—
and sometimes teams keep a specialist as their sixth man.
スペシャリストは
シックスマンに置いたりする
But I've never seen a specialist as extreme as you.
が 君ほど極端な
スペシャリストは見たことがない
あそこまで徹底して１つのことを
極めたのは驚異的だ
It's extraordinary to specialize so thoroughly in a single thing.
But aren't you the one...
君は そこが限界って—
assuming that's your limit?
自分で決めつけてねえか？
It's impressive you can view yourself so objectively and play in that way.
ま そんだけ自分を
客観的に見て—
割り切ってプレーしているのは
大したもんだよ
But you may be taking it too far.
けど 割り切りすぎかもよ
（携帯電話の呼び出し音）
（火神）はい
Hello?
お 火神 足は大丈夫か？
Kagami, are your legs okay?
Yeah.
（火神）うっす
Practice!
つか練習
できなくても顔出せって言ったろ
Didn't I tell you to come even if you couldn't play?
（火神）足が治ったら—
Once my legs heal...
来週から出るんで じゃあ
I'll be there starting next week.
Bye.
（日向）あ おい
Hey!
We're still high schoolers.
（木吉）オレら まだ高校生だぜ
Believe in your own potential a little more.
もっと自分の可能性を信じても
いいんじゃねえの
I'm just talking to myself.
とか独り言 言ってみたりしてな
また来週会おうぜ 黒子君
See you next week, Kuroko.
（黒子）あの
（木吉）ん？
Excuse me.
Yeah?
ああ さっき買ったばっかりなのに
I just bought these!
ちわっす
Hey.
There he is!
（小金井）やっと来たか
心配したんだぞ
We were worried about you.
Kagami, you bastard.
テメエ 火神
マジであれから顔出さなかったな
You really didn't show up after that.
Sorry.
（火神）すいません
だ だから謝るくらいなら
ちゃんと来いって
I-If you're going to apologize,
just come in the first place.
Hey.
（木吉）ウイーッス
さあ 練習しようぜ！
Let's practice.
Good to see you, Kiyoshi.
久しぶりだな 木吉
Yeah!
（木吉）おう
（日向）おう じゃねーよ
Don't give me that.
Why are you wearing your uniform?!
なんでユニフォームなんだよ
オマエ！
I got excited about coming to practice again.
久しぶりの練習で
テンション上がっちまってよ
Are you serious?! Are you?!
やる気あんのか？
あんのか？
Yeah!
（木吉）おう！
（日向）あんのか…
Are you?
I've been in the hospital since last summer.
（木吉）去年の夏から
わけあって 入院しててさ
Because of my surgery and rehab, I've been taking a break.
手術とリハビリで
今まで休んでたんだ
Kiyoshi Teppei, 193 centimeters, 81 kilos.
木吉鉄平 193センチ 81キロ
My position is center.
ポジションはセンター
よろしくな
Nice to meet you.
（降旗）この人が 誠凛バスケ部を
This is the guy who created the Seirin basketball team?
（福田）創った人？
Teppei, you're sure you're okay now?
鉄平 もう大丈夫なのね？
ああ もう完璧治ったよ
Yeah! I'm completely healed.
I may have forgotten some stuff, but I didn't spend my time in the hospital doing nothing.
ブランクはあるけど—
入院中 何もしてなかった
わけじゃねえよ
Oh, did you learn something new?
おっ 何か学んだのか？
Yeah...
Card games.
花札をな
相部屋のじいちゃんに
習ったんだ
The old man sharing my room taught me.
So?
だから？
（木吉）面白いぜ
It's fun.
バスケ関係ねえじゃん！
That's got nothing to do with basketball!
（木吉）
あと これだけは言っとこう
Also, one more thing.
I'm putting my undefeated three year high school career on the line.
なけなしの高校３年間を
懸けるんだ
I'm serious about doing this.
やるからには本気だ
目標はもちろん—
My goal is, of course...
Where is it?
どこだ！
What?
Where's the Inter-High being held?
（木吉）いや
インハイの開催地ってどこ？
毎年変わるし もう負けたわ
It changes every year, and we already lost!
今 目指しているのは
ウインターカップ
We've got our sights set on the Winter Cup now!
Where is that this year?
（木吉）それは 今年どこ？
It's in Tokyo every year!
東京です！ 毎年ね！
This is the guy who created the basketball team...
この人がバスケ部を創った…
Really?
（１年生たち）えええええ
Anyway, if you're going to climb a mountain,
you've got to aim for the summit.
ま とにかく—
山登るなら 目指すのは
当然てっぺんだが—
But let's not forget to enjoy the scenery.
景色もちゃんと楽しんでこうぜ
That's a foul, Kagami.
（リコ）ファウルよ 火神君！
You're too forceful!
強引すぎ！ もっと周りを見て！
Pay more attention to your surroundings!
Doesn't he seem especially on edge?
（小金井）あいつ やけに
ピリピリしてない？
Yeah, at first I thought it was because he's focusing,
ああ 最初は集中してるせいだと
思ったけど どうも違う
but I was wrong.
He's acting like he did when he first joined.
入部したてんときに戻ったみたいだ
He doesn't try to rely on anyone else.
まるで周りに頼ろうとしない
He's playing basketball by himself.
１人でバスケやってやがる
（リコ）どうしちゃったの 火神君
What happened, Kagami?
なあ 火神君
Hey, Kagami.
オレも早く
試合に出たいんだけどさ—
I want to play soon too,
but I don't think it's fair for me to ask to start just because I'm an upperclassman.
上級生だからって—
戻ってすぐ出してくれってのも
横暴だと思うわけさ
だからよ—
So...
Why don't we play some one-on-one for the starting position?
勝負してくんね？ ワンオンワン
スタメン賭けて
What?
木吉…
Kiyoshi...
はあ… 変わってねえなあ
He hasn't changed at all.
This is why I can't stand the guy.
だから ヤなんだよ
あいつは
He always plays hard, is obsessed with basketball, acts stupid, and...
いつだって全力で バスケバカで
ボケてて そんで—
He's always up to something.
いつも何かたくらんでる
Honnouteki naru situation
An instinctive situation,
tatakau imi o sagasu kono imitation
searching for a reason to fight this imitation.
Kurayami kara koboreru raito
Use the light that seeps from the darkness,
torawareta yourself kowase
and break free from your imprisonment.
Jiyuu ukeirete wa mogaite kuratte fuantei
Accept your freedom and struggle through your insecurities.
Kodou ga boku o tsukiage spy kidottenda
The pulsation throws me for a loop and I begin to spy.
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best"
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best."
And Rhythm like this never ends
And Rhythm like this never ends.
Sometimes your voice reached to me
Sometimes your voice reached to me,
Because I don't want to face the fate
because I dont want to face the fate.
Tobi tachitaku naru tte?
You say you wanna jump back up?
Katarurizumu oboete ndarou
You remember the catal rhythm, don't you?
Mune ni hibiku akirame no kako e
To the past resounding resignation in your chest,
Sabita sukoaboodo mitai ni
like a rusty scoreboard,
kimi mo koko de furuete ndarou?
you're shaking, aren't you?
Toriaezu wa mayoi no nai mirai e
For now, confidently head into the future.
Zanzou demo ii nda
Even if it's just a fragment of yourself.
Future aspect
Next Episode
Kiyoshi, are you sure you should be playing one-on-one so soon?
（日向）木吉 いきなり
ワンオンワンって大丈夫なのか？
（木吉）ルールぐらい覚えてるぞ
（日向）そういうことじゃねえよ
I still remember the rules.
That's not the point.
オマエ自分のブランク
考えろっつってんだ
You should think about what you've forgotten.
Oh, are you worried about me?
（木吉）あー
心配してくれてんのか
Episode 20
I Don't Want to Be
（日向）はあ 調子狂うわ…
I've had enough of this...